I got my teacher evaluations. Look what this student wrote.
我剛拿到教師評鑒表 你們聽這個學生寫的
"I loved Dr. Geller's class. Mind-blowing lectures.
「我愛蓋勒博士的課」 「令人大呼過癮」
You are definitely the hottie of the Paleontology Department."
「蓋勒博士」 「您是古生物學系的猛男」
"Hotties of Paleontology." There's a big-selling calendar.
古生物學系的猛男們 做成月曆一定賣
-Who wrote it? -The evaluations are all anonymous.
那是誰寫的？ 我也想知道 但評鑒表是匿名的
-You have their exams? -Yeah.
期末考考卷還在嗎？ 在啊
You could just match the handwriting and there's your admirer.
你可以拿考卷來對筆跡 就知道仰慕者是誰了
A hot girl's at stake and he's Rain Man.
只要和女色有關 他就成了大天才
Wait a minute. Why are we so sure that this is a girl?
等等，為何確定是個女生？
It's a girl!
是女生
But it wouldn't matter.
總之沒差
Because I'm a teacher. She's a student.
因為我是老師 她是學生
-It's illegal? -It's frowned upon.
校規說不行？ 沒有，但是會有爭議 瞭解
-And there's a big age gap. -When you're 90..
而且年齡差那麼多 你就這麼想，等你90歲…
I know,she'll be 80 and it won't seem like such a big difference.
我知道，我90她就80 感覺就差不多了
That's not what I was gonna say.
我不是要說這個
When you're 90, you'll still have the memory of being with a 20-year-old.
我是說等你90歲 還能擁有跟小妹妹戀愛的回憶
The One Where Ross Dates A Student
本集播出：「師生戀」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
-Monica..? -I don't know.
摩妮卡… 我不知道 好吧
You know your college friend who became a movie director?
錢德 你知道你那個 當上導演的大學同學嗎？
Oh yeah, Dana Keystone. She was in my movement class.
知道，黛娜基史東 我們一起修動作課
-What's a movement class? -He's pretending he didn't take mime.
什麼是動作課？ 錢德在假裝他沒修默劇
She's directing a new Al Pacino movie. You gotta get me an audition.
總之她要導艾爾帕西諾的新片 你得幫我爭取試鏡
I haven't talked to her in 10 years.
我不知道，我們10年沒聯絡
Please,Chandler, I would owe you so much.
不，求求你，就當我欠你
You do owe me so much. You owe me 3000..
你本來就欠我 你欠我3千4百…
Hey,hey,dude. Why you changing the subject? What?
老兄 你幹嘛轉移話題？ 什麼？
-Will you make the call? -Okay,I'll try.
你打不打電話？ 好吧，我試試看
Thanks. Last auditions are Thursday, so I gotta get in by Thursday.
謝了，你最好了 試鏡是星期四截止 我星期四之前得過去
Remember Thursday. Remember Thursday?
記得星期四就對了，你記得嗎
Yeah,so Tuesday?
星期二嗎？
Thursday!
是星期四
Just think of it like this: The third day. Monday, one day.
你如果記不住就記是第三天 星期一，一天
Tuesday,two day.
星期二，二天
Wednesday... When day, what day?
星期三，三小  哪一天？
Thursday!
星期四
The third day, okay?
第三天，好嗎？
-Thank you. -Okay.
謝謝你 不客氣
-Hey,Monica..? -She doesn't know.
摩妮卡… 她不知道
-I'm gonna check my messages. -You thought of that in there?
摩妮卡，我要聽留言 你在廁所裡想到這個？
Nature called. She wants to see who else did.
當然，生理需求結束 她想知道還有誰需要她
Hello?
喂？
Rachel.
瑞秋
Someone's in our apartment. Call the cops!
我們家有人，快報警
You're on the phone!
你在用電話
-Oh,my God! -What?
天哪… 怎麼？
Oh,my God! Thank you!
天哪，謝謝你
There was a fire at our place.
是消防隊，家裡失火了
-Oh,my God! How bad was it? -It was a fire,I'm guessing not good.
天哪，有多嚴重？ 他沒說，但失火總是不太妙
-Come on, we gotta go! -Yeah,come on.
快走吧 快點
What are you smiling about?
笑什麼笑？有什麼好笑的？
The part I want to audition for is a fireman. This is so meant to be!
我要應徵的角色是消防隊員 這真是天意
You were very generous with your grades this semester.
你這學期的成績給得很大方喔
-Professor Geller? -Yeah?
蓋勒教授？
-I really enjoyed your class. -Oh,thank you. Thanks very much.
-我很喜歡你的課 -謝謝你，非常感謝
I'm a little embarrassed about calling you a hottie.
不好意思，說你是猛男
-That was you? -Yeah.
-那是你？ -對
I felt a little weird about it. You're a teacher. I'm a student.
我後來覺得怪怪的 你是老師，我是學生
Want to go out sometime?
但或許你願意和我約會？
That's not the best idea.
這樣恐怕不太好
Oh,because I was thinking, the semester's over.
我想說學期結束
-You're not my teacher anymore. -What time?
-你就不是我的老師了 -什麼時候？
Oh,you know what? Forget it.
當我沒說
I see you already gave me an A.
你已經給我A了
-Gotcha. -I'm kidding! God!
-瞭解 -開玩笑的
So seriously, what time?
說真的，什麼時候？
Coming through. Coming through. Oh! Hello. Hi.
借過，借過 你好
Right. Coming through!
不對，借過
Okay. It's not so bad.
還好嘛
Most of the damage was contained to the bedrooms.
災情主要集中在臥房
Hey,buddy, think I could borrow your uniform this Thursday?
老兄 這星期四可以跟你借制服嗎？
-Excuse me? -Joey! He's working.
-什麼？ -喬伊，人家在忙
You would look good in that.
你穿一定很帥
Oh,how bad is it?
災情如何？
It's really bad.
很慘，非常慘
The only thing that isn't burned is an ax, which I do not remember buying.
只有一斧頭沒被燒到 我根本不記得有買過
-How's your room? -Everything's ruined.
瑞秋你呢？ 東西都燒光了
My bed,my clothes. Look at my favorite sweater.
床鋪，衣服 你看我最喜歡的藍毛衣
Isn't that mine?
那不是我的嗎？
Fine. I'm sorry for your loss.
好，我對你的損失深感遺憾
You won't be able to live here for a while. You have a place to stay?
這裡暫時不能住人 你們有地方去嗎？
Oh! Wow!
Okay,look,pal...
好，你給我聽著
I am not in the mood to be hit on right now.
我現在沒心情被搭訕
But if you give me your number, I'll call you sometime.
不過要是你給我電話 我改天會打給你
Yes, they can stay with us.
她們可以跟我們住
Do you know what started the fire, Mr. Fireman?
請問起火原因是什麼？
Well,do either of you smoke?
你們有人抽煙嗎？
No. But yeah, I could use one now. Thanks.
沒有，不過現在來一根也好
-Do you light candles, burn incense? -I do all the time. I love them!
-不是，你們有人點蠟燭焚香嗎 -有，我常點，我很喜歡
Oh,my God, I did it! It's me, it's me! I burned down the house!
天哪，是我害的 我把房子給燒了
Okay,Phoebe,calm down. There's no need to place blame. Okay?
菲比，別激動 沒有必要怪誰，好嗎？
I warned her about those candles.
我警告過她
I can't believe how long it's been.
能聊聊真好，居然這麼久了
Hey,Chandler,is that..?
錢德，是不是…
-Oh,that's great, good for you. -So,is it..?
太好了，恭喜你 聽著…
Okay. So,yeah, maybe we can get together...
好，我們可以見個面…
Hold on for one second.
你等我一下…
What?
怎樣？
Do you want to get a pizza later?
等你講完，要不要叫披薩？
Hi,I'm back.
我回來了
Yeah,that sounds great. We'll do it then. Okay,bye.
聽起來不錯 好，就這麼決定…好，再見
When's my audition? I know it's Thursday, but what time?
我什麼時候試鏡？ 我知道是星期四，但是幾點？
Hi. We didn't get to it.
我們沒聊到那個
I'm taking her to coffee. We'll do it then.
我帶她去喝咖啡時再說
Now you're going on a date with this girl?
你要跟這個女生約會？
I haven't talked to her in 10 years.
這不是約會，我們失聯10年
You can't just call up and ask somebody for a favor.
總不能一通電話過去 就要人家幫忙
There are rules, you know? You gotta put in some time.
要講人情世故，花點時間客套
Right,I'm sorry.
沒錯，對不起
-It's not like she's an ex-girlfriend. -We only went out once.
你又不是去見舊情人 我們只約過一次會
You dated her?!
你跟她交往過？
Not once.
一次也沒有
Why don't I just go out with an ex, you know, and do Joey a favor?
乾脆我也去找個前男友 來幫喬伊的忙
You want to do Joey a favor? Maybe you go out with Joey.
想幫喬伊的忙就跟喬伊約會
That's great. My friend Joey's in the movie business.
真好，我朋友喬伊也在電影圈
You know who I ran into from school? Howie.
你猜我那天遇見誰？豪伊
My friend's name is Joey.
我的朋友叫喬伊
Apparently, Howie's editing now.
豪伊在當剪接師
Yeah,he calls me up and asks me if he can edit my new movie.
他打來問能不能剪我的新片
Can you believe that?
你相信嗎？
You know,I haven't spoken to him in 10 years...
我們10年沒聯絡
and he asks me for a favor?
他居然來找我幫忙
Yeah,I've always hated that Howie.
我一向很討厭那傢伙
No "How you doing?"
連聲好都沒問
Man,I mean,not even a cup of coffee first.
連先喝杯咖啡都沒有
-The nerve. -Yeah.
好大膽 就是啊
Refill?
續杯嗎？
This is last-minute, so I want to apologize for the mess.
事出突然，抱歉房裡一團亂
Oh,who cares?
Oh,my God! It sure didn't look this way when I lived here.
天哪 我住的時候絕對不是長這樣
I know!
我知道
But there's only room for one, so one of you will have to stay at Joey's.
問題是這裡只能睡一個人 另一個人得去住喬伊家
Since the fire was kind of my fault, you should get to stay here.
既然失火是我引起的 你就睡這裡吧
Hey,hey, now. This was no one's fault. It was an accident.
誰也沒有錯，那是個意外
It was my fault. You should get the nice room.
不，是我害的，你應該睡這裡
Okay!
好吧
You're the first guest at "Hotel Monica."
瑞秋，你是本飯店的首位貴客
Hotel Monica!
Just tell me how you like your eggs.
你得告訴我早餐想吃什麼蛋
I thought I'd bring them to you in bed.
我打算端到床上給你
-You've been through so much. -I have.
-你吃了這麼多苦 -就是啊
This right here is where I keep the pizza.
這是我放披薩的地方
And that's where the napkin is.
紙巾在那裡
-What's that smell? -I know! I don't...
什麼味道？ 就是啊
Oh, please, it was such a big class. You never even noticed me.
拜託，那麼大一個班 你根本沒有注意到我
What? Of course I did. You sat next to "Sleepy Sleeperson."
當然有，你坐愛困睡人森旁邊
Who?
誰？
Oh. I had trouble remembering names, so I came up with nicknames.
我記不住全班的名字 就取綽號代替
The guy on the other side of you was "Smelly Von Brown Shirt."
像你的另一邊是發臭馮棕上衣
Oh,yeah.
沒錯
-So did you have a nickname for me? -No. No.
你有幫我取綽號嗎？ 沒有
Yes,you did. What was it?
你有，是什麼？
"Cutie McPretty."
可愛麥美眉
Oh,that's so sweet!
真好
Listen, I gotta tell you, I'm having a great time.
說真的，今晚真的很開心
You said it might be weird, the whole student/teacher thing?
你之前說師生約會很奇怪
And to be frank, I thought it would be too.
其實我也有同感
But it's not. I mean,it's not at all.
結果不會，一點也不會
-Dr. Geller! -Burt!
蓋勒博士 伯特
-Did you sleep well last night? -I did.
你昨晚睡得好嗎？ 很好
Monica was so sweet. She left a little mint on my pillow.
摩妮卡還在我的枕頭上 放了一小片薄荷
Know what Joey left on my pillow?
你猜喬伊在我枕頭上放什麼？
Gum.
口香糖
-We determined the cause of the fire. -I know. It was my candle,my candle!
-找到起火原因了 -我知道，是我的蠟燭害的
No,there was an appliance left on. It looks like a curling iron.
不是，浴室有個電器沒拔掉 好像是卷髮器
-I don't use a curling iron. -Someone does.
-我沒在用卷髮器 -總有人在用
Don't look at me, my hair's straight. Straight,straight,straight.
別看我，我的頭髮是直的 直的直的直的
-It could've been a hair straightener. -Oh.
也可能是直髮夾
This is where I keep the pizza.
披薩都放這裡
And.. Hey,where'd the napkin go?
紙巾呢？
What is that?
什麼味道？
Is that old shrimp?
是臭掉的蝦子嗎？
I think it is!
應該是喔
I wouldn't want my best guest to strain her eyes.
好了，可不能讓貴客眼睛疲勞
Thanks,Monica.
謝謝摩妮卡
-Does that smell bother you? -From Joey's?
-你怕那個味道嗎？ -喬伊家的味道？
I can hardly smell it over here.
這裡又聞不到
Well, you let me know if you can. I can bake a pie to cover it.
聞得到就說 我可以烤個派把它蓋過去
-I can smell it a little, bake a pie. -Okay.
-有點聞得到，烤個派吧 -好
Hello?
喂？
One minute,please. It's the fire inspector.
在，請稍候 火場調查員找你
Hello? Yeah, this is Phoebe.
喂？我是菲比
Really?
是嗎？
Yeah, so it turns out that it wasn't the hair straightener...
是的，所以直髮夾...
that started the fire.
不是起火點
No,no. It was the candles.
不，是蠟燭
Yeah. It's very not good leaving candles unattended.
把蠟燭點著不管實在不太好
In fact,one of the first things they teach you in fire school is...
消防學校最先教的事情之一…
okay, well I have to go now.
好，我該掛了
We had such a great time. She's incredible.
我們玩得好開心，她好棒
I thought the age difference might be a problem, but it wasn't.
我以為年齡會造成問題 結果一點也不會
Elizabeth is very mature for her age.
伊麗莎白非常成熟
A concept lost on some people.
有些人就是不懂
It's okay to date a student?
所以師生可以約會
Well,not really. Technically, it's not against the rules.
也不是，技術上沒觸犯校規
But it's frowned upon, especially by the professor we saw last night:
但是會受爭議 尤其是我們昨晚遇見的教授
"Judgy Von Holier-than-thou."
愛批評馮比你高尚
You don't want to get a reputation as "Professor McNails-his-students."
羅斯，小心一點 別被叫成麥泡學生教授
-Yeah. What should I do? -Well,it seems pretty clear.
-我該怎麼辦？ -很簡單
What's more important? What people think or how you feel?
什麼比較重要？ 別人的看法還是你的感覺？
-You gotta follow your heart. -Joey,that's so sweet.
你得忠於你的心 喬伊，你說得真好
-Hi. -Hey! So how'd it go with Dana?
你跟黛娜談得怎樣？
Any reason I should leave a block of time open? Say,Thursday?
我星期四該不該空出時間來？
-I couldn't do it. -You couldn't do it?
-我說不出口 -你說不出口？
I need more time. We're going to dinner.
別急，我需要更多時間 我們晚上要吃飯
You're going out with her again?
什麼？你還要跟她出去
-Going out with who? -Dana Keystone, from college.
跟誰出去？ 大學的黛娜基史東
Oh,yeah. Wasn't she...?
她不是…
No,that was Dana Kaplan.
那是黛娜卡普林
Oh.
-Joey, you didn't even know her! -Yeah,whatever.
喬伊，你根本不認識她 隨便啦
Great story again.
故事真的好棒
The yarns that you weave!
好錯綜複雜
You know, actually, I should get going.
我該走了
Oh,no,no,stay! Because you should stay.
留下來，你應該留下來
Oh,I am really flattered.
我真的很受寵若驚
But I just... I don't feel that way about you.
但是我對你沒感覺
Oh,no,no. That's not..
不，我不是…不是
I'm sorry, Chandler. You know, you're such a sweet guy...
錢德，對不起 你人很好...
and I don't want to hurt you.
我也不想傷害你
I wish I could do something to make you feel better.
真想設法讓你好過一點
No.. Really?
不…真的嗎？
Of course.
當然
Well,it just hurts so bad, I...
我真是太傷心了，我…
Oh,I'm sorry.
對不起
-Maybe there is one thing you can do. -What? Anything. Anything.
-或許你可以做一件事 -什麼事？你儘管說
Well, I mean, this is just off the top of my head now.
我是剛剛才想到的
But I have this friend.. This actor friend.
我有個演員朋友
He would kill me if he knew that I was doing this.
他要是知道一定會殺了我
But...
但...
would it be possible for him to audition for your movie on Thursday?
你可不可能讓他去試鏡 就星期四吧？
Absolutely.
沒問題
But...
但是...
you'd really feel better if your friend could audition for my movie?
我讓你的朋友來試鏡 真的能讓你好過一點？
The heart wants what it wants. Bye.
這是我的心願，再見
Hey! How's it going?
怎麼樣啊？
Well,not much has changed in the last five minutes.
這5分鐘都沒什麼變化
Yes,it has. I made cookies!
其實有，我烤了餅乾
I'm still full from your homemade potato chips.
不了，我還在消化你做的薯片
But you should eat them now, because they're hot from the oven.
但是餅乾應該剛烤好就趁熱吃
Okay.
好
But not in here! Can't eat them in bed,remember? No crumbies!
但不是在這裡 床上不能吃餅乾，不能掉屑屑
Oh. Okay,I'll be out in a second.
好，我馬上出去
Okay.
好
-What are you doing? -This doesn't lock,does it?
-你在幹什麼？ -門不能鎖對吧？
-Oh! Joey,I'm sorry. -It's all right,don't worry about it.
-喬伊，對不起  -沒關係，別在意
But look! That's gonna leave a stain.
但是你看，會有印子
Rach, hey, it's fine. You're at Joey's.
瑞秋，沒關係，這是喬伊家
-Really? -Yeah, look.
真的嗎？ 當然，你看
Yeah.
-I've never lived like this before. -I know.
-我沒有這樣吃過東西  -我知道
Well,don't waste it. I mean, it's still food.
別浪費了，這是食物
What do you want to do now? Want to get a drink?
接著要幹嘛？要不要去喝酒？
I can't.
我不行
-Oh,you have some studying to do? -No,I have some turning 21 to do.
-你要唸書？ -不是，我要滿21歲
You know, I remember when I was in college,we used to..
我以前念大學時，我們都…
-What are you doing? -Nothing, I'm so comfortable with you.
你幹什麼？ 沒事，我只是覺得好舒服
Do you not want to be seen with me?
你怕被別人看見？
No,of course I do. Are they gone?
什麼？當然不是 他們走了嗎？
No,they're still here. But I think I'm about to leave.
他們還在，不過我要走了
What? No,no,wait,wait..
什麼？等一下
You're right, this is stupid. Who cares what people think?
你說得對，這樣太蠢了 管別人怎麼想
I mean, we like each other, right?
我們情投意合，對吧？
There's nothing wrong with that.
這樣並沒有錯
Come on.
走吧
Burt. Lydia. Mel.
伯特，莉蒂亞，梅爾
-This is Elizabeth. -Hi.
這位是伊麗莎白
Aren't you in my popular culture class?
你不是有修我的大眾文化？
That's right, Lydia. Elizabeth is a student.
沒錯，伊麗莎白是學生
And we're dating.
我們在交往
And you may frown upon that but...
你們可以皺眉搖頭
we're not gonna hide it anymore.
但我們不會再躲了
You are so fired.
你的飯碗砸定了
-What? -They'll fire you.
-什麼？-你會被解聘
You can't date her. It's against the rules.
跟學生交往是違規的
Really? It's not just frowned upon?
真的？不只是受爭議？
I love it at Joey's!
我最喜歡喬伊家了
-Nice! -Thanks.
漂亮 謝謝
So you busy Thursday?
你星期四有事嗎？
Oh,very funny. Remember? My audition was supposed to be Thursday.
真好笑，不曉得你記不記得 我的試鏡就是星期四
You got me the audition? Let's hug it up!
你幫我爭取到了？來抱抱
Okay,okay! What are you gonna do to me if you get the part?
要是你入選還得了
-Hey. -Hi.
Yeah,okay,I need to talk to you.
我有事要找你
I know they said the hair straightener started the fire.
我知道他們說直髮夾是起火點
But I think I'm partly at fault.
但我也有責任
You see,I didn't tell you, but...
我沒有告訴你
I had recently refilled the tissues.
我放了新的衛生紙
And so,let's face it, that's just kindling.
那個太容易著火了
So I think it's fair that I stay at Joey's.
所以我應該來住喬伊家
No, no, no, this was my fault.
不，菲比，都是我不好
-Besides,I'm fine here. -Okay.
-而且我在這裡好得很 -好吧…
-Chandler,Monica's looking for you. -Really?
-錢德，摩妮卡在找你 -是喔？
-She said something about crumbies. -No,no,no! I was so careful.
好像跟餅乾屑有關 不會吧，我那麼小心
You have to switch with me. Monica is driving me crazy.
你一定要跟我換 摩妮卡快把我逼瘋了
That's right. All the ladies want to stay at Joey's.
是的，小姐們都想住喬伊家
No,I don't want to switch.
不要，我不想換
Please! I can throw wet paper towels here!
拜託啦，我在這裡可以扔紙巾
No,but at Monica's, you can eat cookies over the sink.
在對面你可以對著水槽吃餅乾
I know. I'm sorry.
我知道，對不起
All right,fine.
算了
This looks like so much fun. God,what a mess.
這個好像很好玩，濕答答的
Wow, it actually is in the handbook.
校規裡真的有
I can't date you or have a hot plate in my office.
我不能和你約會 或是在研究室放電磁爐
I can't believe we have to stop seeing each other.
我們居然不能再見面了
For what it's worth, I did appreciate you standing up for me.
不過謝謝你為我挺身而出
That felt really nice.
我好感動
Kind of made me like you even more.
我更喜歡你了
I know,I know. I really like you too. But we can't date.
我知道，我也很喜歡你 但是我們不能交往
It's against the rules. It's forbidden.
校規明文禁止師生戀
-Wow. -What?
怎麼了？
Just hearing you describe it as "forbidden"...
光聽你說校規禁止
it's really hot.
就覺得好性感
Really?
真的？
Yeah.
對
Well,I don't care how hot it is, it's wrong.
不管有多性感，這都是錯的
-Stop it. -No,no. It's wrong.
-別再說了 -不，這是錯的
It's naughty.
這樣很壞
It's...
這是...
taboo.
禁忌
Shut the book.
把書合起來
Hey. Let's also get a hot plate.
再去弄個電磁爐吧
Hey.
-So? -So...?
怎樣啊？ 怎樣？
It's Thursday! How was the audition?
今天是星期四，試鏡結果如何
It's.. Monday, one day. Tuesday, two day. Wednesday,what day..
啥？星期一一天，星期二二天 星期三三小？星期四…
Oh!